SRIKUMAR S

+91 86100 56926



srikumar.s@outlook.in



Application program Engineer

A block, S15, Prabhavathi Merdian, Electronic city, Bangalore - 560100



SUMMARY

A goal oriented professional with 6.5 years of experience in development of mobile and web based applications Specialized in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, ReactJS, Core API development Experience in various phases including analysis, design, development, unit testing, implementation and production support. Self-motivated reliable, able to learn new technology and technical skills quickly. Seeking a position to utilize my skills and abilities in the industry that offers professional growth while being resourceful, innovative, and flexible.

EDUCATION

Computer Science Engineering

79%

Adithya Institute of Technology 2014 – 2018

HSC

60%

NAMMHRS School 2012 - 2013

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript/jQuery
- Web Components (LIT)
- SQL
- PHP
- · Core Java
- Kafka
- OpenSearch
- Mambu
- AWS
- · Core API development

CERTIFICATIONS

- 2018/08 DELL EMC2 Data Associate
- 2018/11 PHP / MySQL Training Udemy
- Scrum Professional Certificate Program

WORK EXPERIENCE

UNO Digital Bank - Application program Engineer

May 2023 - Present

I-Exceed Technologies - Senior Software Engineer

JUL 2022 -Dec 2022

Turbo Technologies - Software Engineer

May 2020 - JUL 2022

Virudhu Infotech - Software Engineer

Jun 2018 - Apr 2020

PROJECTS

Prime App

- Prime App is an application that is developed using Appzillon (a low code visual development platform), Java, Javascript, Jquery, CSS. This tapp contains all the Android and IOS plugin features of Appzillon. This app will be the first application to test new product version
- This app will be the first application to test new product version release or to test any changes done in the product level. I worked on front end, screen, interface mapping in this app development Integrated Core APIs to enhance functionality and ensure seamless data flow between front-end and back-end systems.

Microapp Seggregation- Front end Development

- In Appzillon IDE, Microapp is a module based project which contains a particular feature of an application and it can be reused in other applications.
- Worked on the Seggregation of Bankadmin and Corporateuser monolithic applications to microapps using Javascript, Jquery, CSS
- Designed and implemented APIs for app metadata management and user customization preferences.

Appzillon Repository and Customizer

- Appzillon Repository is an internal app store for the applications that is developed using Appzillon IDE. This was developed using Javascript, Java, Jquery, CSS. This app store has both APK and IPA.
- Developed various functionalities such as download, upload, svn browse, related app suggestion, adding favorites, app details and maintenance
- Customizer is a widget-based module in the user dashboard which contains many customizable widgets which is developed using Appzillon IDE, Javascript, Jquery.
- The user will be able to customize his dashboard by dragging and dropping the widgets from the customizer and also, he will be able to remove the widgets from dashboard.

Web-Apps

- Delivering responsive, cross-browser compatible and accessibility compliant websites, achieving 19% faster load time than industry average.
- Designing dynamic, browser compatible pages and reusable markup using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, and JavaScript.
- Expanding features, refine code, and improve processes, producing smoother operations and enhancing user engagement.
- Ensure efficient web development by supporting designers and app developers while resolving website performance issues
- · Actively listened to customers, handled concerns quickly, and escalated major issues to the supervisor.
- Services Based o Worked as a web designer creating a static and dynamic website like WordPress, Joomla, and Experience with installation of customized Experience with website optimization and speed handling... Php (Core), Photoshop, WordPress.
- · Worked within applicable standards, policies, and regulatory guidelines to promote a safe working environment.
- · Increased customer satisfaction by resolving issues.
- Identified issues, analyzed information, and provided solutions to problems.
- Learned new skills and applied them to daily tasks to improve efficiency and productivity.
- Built and integrated APIs to support dynamic content loading and user interactions.

DECLARATION

I announce that the information and details shared in this resume are correct and inclusive. I take full liability for the correctness of the information.